《诉讼双雄》前情提要
我可不欠哈维什么
I don't owe Harvey shit.
也许是他还了我的清白
He may have gotten me out,
但当初他也是卡梅隆的帮凶
but he and Cameron put me in there in the first place.
没错  你不欠哈维的
You're right, you don't owe Harvey,
但你欠我的  因为你被冤枉的事
but you do owe me because I didn't have anything
跟我没有关系
to do with putting you in there,
可我不惜违法把你救了出来
but I broke the law to get you out.
我是来夸奖你摆脱希拉·赛斯的方式的
I came here to compliment you on getting rid of Sheila Sazs.
如果她在庭审前没有回来
If she's not back by the start of trial,
我会认为你想被起诉
I'm gonna assume you want to be brought up on charges.
我只是过来给你这个限制令
I just stopped by to give you this restraining order
阻止你在路易·利特的律师不在场的情况下接触他
preventing you from contacting Louis Litt.
你休想再继续挑拨我和我的人了
You're done driving a wedge between me and my people.
如果我为自己辩护  那我在庭上的每一秒
If I represent myself, every second I'm up there
他们都会看到我就是个律师
they're gonna see me as a lawyer.
但如果她在其中任何一刻
And if she rattles you
打乱你的阵脚
For one of those goddamn seconds,
他们就会认为你是个骗子
they're gonna see you as a fraud
并且再也不会看到你的其他方面
and they're never gonna see you as anything else.
迈克·罗斯有没有到哈佛大学法学院上过学
Did Mike Ross go to Harvard Law School or not?
我要使用宪法第五修正案赋予我的权利
I'd like to assert my Fifth Amendment right.
如果我在陪审团  我会认定你有罪
If I was on that jury, I'd find you guilty.
他们不会允许我
They're not gonna let me change my goddamn lawyer
在庭审过程换律师的
in the middle of a trial.
我们得想办法让他们允许
We need to figure out a way to make them,
因为如果我们想不出  就会输
'cause if we don't, we're gonna lose.
你有最后一个自救的机会
You have one last chance to save yourself.
打电话给我  以免太迟了
Call me before it's too late.
好了  我们有一个计划
Okay, so we have a plan for you
可以让你开始为自己辩护
to start representing yourself.
还缺个能在执行时乱了吉布斯阵脚的办法
We just need a way to rattle Gibbs when we execute it.
我有个办法  但是
I have a way, but...
你不会喜欢的
you're not gonna like it.
我要让克利福德·丹纳出庭作证
I'm gonna call Clifford Danner to the stand.
不行  太冒险了
No way, it's too risky.
-哈维  听我说  -他很愤怒还不稳定
- Harvey, listen to me-- - he's angry and volatile
而且我提醒你
and in case you forgot,
你曾经蠢到把你的秘密告诉别人
he's one of the people you were dumb enough
他就是其中之一
to tell your secret to.
这些我都知道
I know all of that,
但你自己也说  我们需要同情
but you said it yourself, we need sympathy,
没有人比我们从监狱里救出来的无辜之人
and no one is gonna get us more sympathy
更能给我们挣到同情了
than the innocent guy we got out of prison.
哈维  你说过这件事我必须自己去做
Harvey, you said I needed to do this.
这就是我做事的方式
Well, this is how I do it.
你对我有信心吗
Do you have faith in me or not?
格洛丽亚·丹纳夫人吗
Mrs. Gloria Danner?
-是的  -你好  我叫迈克·罗斯
- Yes. - Hi, my name is Mike Ross.
我是皮-斯-利律师事务所的律师  我想
I'm a lawyer at Pearson Specter Litt and I was hoping--
我知道你是谁
I know who you are,
我也知道你来做什么
and I know what you're doing here.
你是来让克利福德出庭为你作证的
You've come to get Clifford to testify for you,
但他恐怕去不了
but I'm afraid he's not going to.
拜托了  女士  我保证
Please, ma'am, I promise you,
地检官不能重开他的案子
the D.A. cannot reopen his case--
我不是怕地检官
I'm not talking about the district attorney.
我儿子死了  罗斯先生
My son's dead, Mr. Ross.
什么
What?
克利福德三周前被枪杀了  所以
Clifford was shot and killed three weeks ago, so...
很抱歉  他帮不了你了
I'm sorry, he can't help you.
-你好  -你在办公室吗
- Hello? - Are you in the office?
现在是周四晚上  我在看我的节目
It's Thursday night. I'm watching my show.
录下来晚点看  我需要你帮忙
Well, then goddamn tivo it because I need your help.
你用这种语气跟我说话  最好事情很重要
It better be important if you're taking that tone with me.
如果这是麻将馆的事...
And if this is about that mah-jongg game--
我才不在乎什么该死的麻将
I don't give a shit if it's mah-jongg
宫爆鸡丁还是跳棋
or kung pao or chinese checkers.
这是你这一辈子
This is the most important thing
我会让你做的最重要的事
that I'm ever gonna ask you to do in your entire life.
给我下命令吧
Give me an order.
我要你用尽一切办法
I need you to pull whatever strings you have
帮我搞到迈克这个案子的庭审记录
to get me a transcript of Mike's trial
并且对此保密
and I need you to keep it to yourself.
介意我问一下你要这个做什么吗
Mind if I ask what you need it for?
因为我得知道我们有没有一丁点机会
Because I need to know if we have a snowball's chance in hell
打赢这个官司
of winning this thing.
辩方准备好传唤第一位证人了吗
Is defense ready to call its first witness?
准备好了  法官大人
I am, Your Honor.
什么
What?
我要传唤证人了
I'm calling my witness.
控方对此有什么疑问吗
Does prosecution have a problem with that?
反对  这太过分了  法官大人
Objection, this is outrageous, Your Honor.
他们不能在庭审中途换律师
They can't switch attorneys in the middle of a trial.
你说得对  但事实上
And that would be true except for the fact
我从一开始就是这个案子的联席律师
that I've been co-counsel on this case from day one.
联席律师  你在说什么
Co-counsel? What planer are you living on?
皮-斯-利律师事务所是我的辩护律师
The one where Pearson Specter Litt is my attorney of record.
这是员工任务分配书
I have the employee directory right here.
里面有我的名字
My name is in it.
此案开审以来就在这里了
It's been there since the beginning of this trial,
你如果想要反对我
and if you wanted to object to me,
应该在开庭的时候
you would have had to have done it
就提出反对
at the beginning of this trial.
那我要他们放弃一切申请无效审判的权利
Then I want them waiving all rights to a mistrial
并且记录在案
and I want it in the record.
法官大人  我不能因为
Your Honor, I'm not gonna be punished
她不知道我从头到尾
just because she didn't understand
都是自己的辩护律师而受到惩罚
that I've been representing myself this whole time.
他说得有道理  吉布斯女士
He's got a point, Ms. Gibbs.
那基于他为自己辩护的基础上
Then I want them waiving all rights to a mistrial
我要他们放弃一切申请无效审判的权利
based on him representing himself.
乐意之至  法官大人  因为我根本
My pleasure, Your Honor, 'cause I don't expect
不认为我们需要申请无效审判
we'll be needing a mistrial at all.
那就传唤你的第一个证人吧
Then call your first witness.
辩方请求传唤格洛丽亚·丹纳出庭作证
Defense would like to call Gloria Danner to the stand.
请告诉陪审团你的姓名
Please state your name for the jury.
格洛丽亚·丹纳
Gloria Danner.
丹纳夫人
Mrs. Danner,
数年前  你的儿子克利福德
A number of years ago, your son Clifford
被判谋杀罪入狱
was convicted of murder and sentenced to prison,
-对吗  -是的
- is that right? - Yes.
他是无辜入狱的
For a crime he didn't commit.
如果他被判有罪
How do you know he didn't commit it
你怎么知道他是无辜的呢
if he was convicted of it?
因为你证明了他无罪
Because you proved he didn't.
丹纳女士  你能告诉陪审团
Mrs. Danner, can you tell the jury
为什么今天是你出庭作证
why it is that you're here today testifying
而不是你儿子克利福德吗
and not your son Clifford?
他那天在餐馆加班
He was working late at the diner.
那是他出狱之后唯一能找到的工作
It was the only place he could get a job when he got out.
有两个人来抢劫餐馆
Two men came in to rob the place,
克利福德想要阻止他们
and when Clifford tried to stop them,
结果被枪杀了
he was shot and killed.
我深表遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我这辈子含辛茹苦
I worked my whole life
供他上学
to put him through school
结果他却死在
and he ends up dying
那家破餐馆
in the back of that shit restaurant
■
本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
死在那么个破地方
in that shit part of town.
你能告诉陪审团你今天为什么
Can you tell the jury why you agreed
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
愿意过来为我分享你的故事吗
to come share your story for me today?
监狱
Prison
毁了克利福德的一生
ruined Clifford's life...
如果你从一开始就是我们的律师的话
And if you had been our lawyer from day one,
他根本不会被判有罪
he never would have been convicted in the first place.
谢谢你  格洛丽亚
Thank you, Gloria.
没有其他问题了  法官大人
No more questions, Your Honor.
丹纳女士
Mrs. Danner,
我恰好很熟悉你儿子的案子
I happen to be familiar with your son's case.
我知道为了重审该案
And I understand that in order to reopen it,
罗斯先生冒了将他的刑期增加到无期的风险
Mr. Ross risked increasing his sentence to life.
是这样的
That's correct.
我想知道如果他赌输了
Well, I'd like to know how you'd have felt
你会是什么感觉
if he lost that gamble.
我会彻底绝望
I'd have been devastated.
如果真的是那样  而你又发现
And if that happened, how would you have felt
罗斯先生根本就不是个律师
if you then found out
那你又会是什么感觉
that Mr. Ross wasn't even a lawyer after all?
反对  法官大人
Objection, Your Honor,
她可以问多少假设性的问题
how many hypotheticals can she ask?
没关系
That's okay.
我觉得这里的每个人都知道
I think everybody in this courtroom knows
那会是什么感觉
how they would feel.
我没有问题了  法官大人
No more questions, Your Honor.
我根本不会在乎那张纸
I wouldn't have cared what a piece of paper had to say,
因为罗斯先生是我唯一碰到
because Mr. Ross is the only lawyer I ever ran into
愿意帮我儿子的律师
that ever gave a damn about my son.
罗斯先生  你还要传唤第二位证人吗
Mr. Ross, would you care to call your next witness?
我想不到比这位
I can't imagine anyone
更适合的证人了  法官大人
being more eloquent than that, Your Honor.
辩方没有证人了
Defense rests.
翻译：小憨加油    王大可   杨一勾  Reginamoon  肉松
翻译：feilixiaozi   Charl   某羽  校对：油炸电风扇   小酸奶
时间轴：风吹来的那片云
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第十五集
诉讼双雄
第五季第十五集
在发愁结案陈词吗
Having trouble with your closing?
没有  只是正常的步骤而已
No, it's just part of the process.
如果我跟你说今天看到你
Would it make you feel better if I told you
在庭上的表现让我感到前所未有的自豪
that I have never felt more proud of my future husband
这会让你好受点吗
than I did watching you up there today?
会的
Yes, it would.
那就好
Good.
因为我想跟你谈谈你的结案陈词
Because I want to talk to you about your closing.
别跟我说你想让陪审团裁定法律无效
Don't tell me you want me to go with jury nullification.
让陪审团同情你
There is nothing wrong with getting a jury
并没有什么错
to sympathize with you,
迈克  你的父母死于车祸
and, Mike, your parents died in a car accident.
每个人都会同情你的
Who isn't gonna feel for a person like that?
瑞秋  这么做的唯一问题是
Rachel, the only problem with me saying,
"放过我吧因为我童年不幸"这种话
"Let me off because tragedy struck me as a child"
基本等于我承认了自己有罪
is I've pretty much admitted that I'm guilty.
不  区别在于  那场车祸正是
No, the difference is that that accident is the reason
你想要成为一名律师的原因
that you wanted to become a lawyer in the first place.
他们不仅会谅解你  也会因此喜欢你
And they won't just understand it, they will love you for it.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
因为我就是这样
Because I love you for it.
跟他们讲你的故事
Tell them your story and I am telling you,
他们会放过你
they'll let you go.
路易  你找我
Louis, you wanted to see me?
那是几个小时前的事了
Yeah, that was hours ago.
我们得谈谈  现在就得谈
We need to talk. We need to talk right now.
-谈什么  -就谈迈克·罗斯
- About what? - About the fact that
突然开始为自己辩护这件事
Mike Ross is all of a sudden representing himself.
这有什么好谈的
And why exactly do we need to talk about that?
因为这就意味着哈维认为自己要输了
Because it means Harvey thinks he's gonna lose.
这其中的逻辑关系是什么
You wanna walk me through that logic?
哈维这辈子都没有放弃过自己案子的掌控权
Harvey's never given up control of a case in his life,
如果他现在这么做了
and if he's doing that now,
说明他想把失败的记录留给迈克
it means he wants that loss on Mike's record.
路易  在这种时候
Louis, at a time like this,
哈维是不会在乎记录的
Harvey doesn't care about records.
胡扯  我反复读过庭审记录了
Bullshit. I read the transcript backwards and forwards.
他肯定认为他要输了
He thinks he's gonna lose.
路易  到底发生了什么事
Louis, what's really going on here?
我告诉你发生了什么
I'll tell you what's going on.
如果哈维认为我们会输
If Harvey thinks we're gonna lose,
那我们一定会输  如果那样的话
then we'll lose, and if that happens,
你也知道吉布斯下一个目标会是谁
you know who Gibbs is coming after next.
路易  如果真到了那个时候我们再想办法
Louis, we will deal with that when and if she does,
但我告诉你
but I am telling you,
哈维让迈克掌控大局并不是他放弃了
Harvey letting Mike take the reins is not him giving up.
而是他成长了
It's him growing up
并且意识到这个胜利不该由他摘取
and realizing he is not the one to bring this home.
你想聊聊吗
Do you want to talk about it?
聊什么
Talk about what?
我说不好  没准可以聊聊
Oh, I don't know, maybe the fact
迈克正在准备一个可以让他
that Mike is working on a closing
免除牢狱之灾的结案陈词
to keep himself out of jail
而你却没有在帮他
and you're not working on it with him.
我没什么可帮得了  唐娜
There's nothing for me to do, Donna.
这件事交给他了
It's in his hands.
交给他
In his hands?
哈维  那是个庭审策略
Harvey, that was a trial maneuver.
但并不意味着你不能在他需要时帮助他
It doesn't mean you can't help him when he needs you.
-他不需要我  -他这个时候最需要你
- He doesn't need me. - He needs you more than ever.
不  他不需要  是时候让他
No, he doesn't, and it's time for him
脱离二线真正参与进来了
to put the clipboard down and get in the game.
-哈维  -唐娜  这事不仅是
- Harvey-- - Donna, this wasn't just
把证词塞进结案陈词这么简单
some move to slip testimony in.
这关系到迈克的人生
This is Mike's life.
那是他的故事  必须要他自己来讲
It's his story and he needs to be the one to tell it.
至今为止他做的每件事都是在为这一刻做准备
Everything he's done up until now has prepared him for this,
而且我可以很肯定的说
and I'm telling you,
他准备好了
he's ready for it.
辩方准备好做结案陈词了吗
Is defense ready for closing statements?
迈克
Mike?
你还好吗
You okay?
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross?
是的  法官大人
Oh, uh, yes, Your Honor.
陪审团的各位女士们  先生们
Um, ladies and gentleman of the jury,
我想我们
I think most of us...
你们中的大多数在早前的庭审中都听说了
You guys heard evidence earlier in the trial
我可以过目不忘
that I have a photographic memory,
确实如此  但在具体操作中
and I do, but the way it works--
我并不是将我所看到的所有东西都记住
I don't just take a snapshot of something.
而是我要先阅读
See, I read it
然后理解它
and then I understand it,
一旦我理解了
and once I understand it,
我就不会忘记
then I never forget it,
我试图记住我的陈述词
but I've been trying to memorize my speech,
但我记不住
but I can't
因为这都是胡扯
because it's bullshit,
因为我
because I...
我简直一团糟
I am bullshit.
事实上  我确实是个骗子
You see, the truth is--is that I am guilty of being a fraud.
我这辈子都想要成为一个律师
My whole life I have wanted to be a lawyer
然后去帮助那些像克利福德·丹纳一样的人
so that I could help people like Clifford Danner.
那些无从获得支持的人
People who have no one else to fight for them.
那些不被信任的人
No one who believes in them,
但与此同时  我作为律师所做的事
but instead, all I've done as a lawyer
只是日夜不停的工作
is work night and day
好让那些富有的人获得更多财富
to put money into the hands of rich people.
我被赋予了一种天赋  但我却浪费了它
I was given a gift and I wasted it,
我为自己感到羞耻
and I'm ashamed of myself.
同时我还不知收敛
And--and as a final insult,
将这位悲伤地女士拖到众人面前
I paraded this mourning woman out in front of you
只是为了让你们喜欢我
just as a way to get you to admire me.
我很抱歉  格洛丽亚
I am so sorry, Gloria.
我能承诺的
And all I can say
只有无论这些人
is that I promise you,
裁定我有罪与否
whether these people find me innocent or not,
我都会将我的余生
I am gonna spend the rest of my life
致力于为世界上所有的克利福德·丹纳而战
fighting for the Clifford Danners of this world.
我不会再浪费我的天赋了
I will not waste that gift again.
不管你们相不相信
You could believe it or not,
但我是个律师
but I am a lawyer,
而且我会一直做下去
and I always will be.
谢谢
Thank you.
这真是件有趣的事情
Well, it's an interesting thing, really,
看着罪犯们是如何玩弄我们的感情的
how criminals can play with our emotions.
迈克·罗斯能说会道
Mike Ross is articulate
很有煽动力  也很有激情
and persuasive and passionate
听着他的总结陈词
and listening to his closing argument,
我自己差点都想放他一马了
I almost want to let him go myself,
唯独有一个问题  他是个骗子
except for one thing: he's a liar.
他并没有一周一次往返于哈佛
He didn't commute to Harvard one day a week
却可笑地声称自己那么做了
as he so laughably claims.
他没上过大学
He didn't go to college.
没有任何纸质文件能证明他被录取
There is no paper record of his enrollment,
也没有他申请法学院的文件
no applications to law school,
年册里没有他的照片
no picture in the yearbook,
也没有他的班级排名
no class rankings,
甚至没有一个人记得他
no one at all who even remembers him.
除了他那个负债累累的朋友
Except for that one indebted friend
满嘴跑火车
with a lot to lose,
假如你们相信他的证词的话
and if you believe his testimony,
我这还有一堆谎言可以说给你们听
I got a bridge over Brooklyn I'd like to sell you.
不管他承不承认
And whether he says it or not,
他就是指望着
he's banking on the fact
你们将这事看作是一起无受害人犯罪
that you are gonna think this is a victimless crime,
但假如你们宣告他无罪
but if you acquit him,
你们就是允许大家说
you are giving permission to everyone to say
"嘿  我要去装成一个律师"
"hey, I'm gonna pretend to be a lawyer."
"我想说自己是个医生"
"I think I'm gonna say I'm a doctor."
"你猜怎么着
"Hell, you know what?
今天我要装成一名飞行员"
Today, I'm gonna pose as a pilot."
想象一下有一天你在手术台上醒来
Imagine if one day you woke up on the operating table
却发现那个要划开你的胸腔的人
to discover the man who was about to crack open your chest
不是个真正的医生
is not really a doctor.
有罪
Guilty.
你们可得弄清楚
Make no mistake about it,
迈克·罗斯觉得自己比你们厉害
Mike Ross thinks he's better than you.
他觉得自己不用和你们遵守一样的规矩
He thinks he doesn't have to play by the same rules,
但我们知道他是要的
but we know he does.
因为  陪审团的女士们和先生们
Because, ladies and gentleman of the jury,
迈克·罗斯...
Mike Ross...
是个骗子
is a fraud.
迈克...
Mike...
迈克
Mike.
她很厉害  哈维
She was good, Harvey.
-没错  但你也是啊  -你做得很好
- Yeah, so were you. - You were great.
她更厉害  她所说的一切都是真的
She was better. Everything she said was true
而陪审团也知道这一点
and the jury knows it.
不  他们不知道
No they don't.
听着  从我遇见你的那天起
Look, ever since the day I met you,
你就一直能看见人性中的闪光点
you have always seen the good in people,
而我们只需要陪审团中有一个人
and we only need one person on the jury
能感受到你的闪光点
to feel that way about you.
-假如他们感受不到呢  -无所谓
- And what if they don't? - It doesn't matter.
因为无论如何我们也无法改变局面了
Because we can't do anything about it anyways.
所以我们出去吧
So, let's get out of here.
-我不能  -什么叫你不能
- I can't. - What do you mean you can't?
我是说  在陪审团回来前我不能离开
I mean, I can't leave until that jury comes back.
迈克  他们也许几天都回不来
Mike, they might not come back for days.
我不知道该怎么和你说  哈维
I don't know what to tell you, Harvey,
但我不能离开这里
but I can't leave here.
没关系的  哈维
It's okay, Harvey.
听着
Look,
迈克  假如我们真的没时间了
Mike, if we really don't have time,
我不想把时间浪费在这里
I don't want to waste it here.
瑞秋  假如我离开了
Rachel, if I leave,
我满脑子只会想着
all I'm gonna be thinking about
仲裁室里发生了什么
is what's happening in that jury room.
那我去给我俩弄点吃的来
Then I am going to go and get us some food
然后我们一起吃点东西
and we're gonna have a bite to eat
因为我不会白白浪费这段时间的
because I'm not gonna let this time go to waste.
好吧
Okay.
-怎么了  -什么怎么了
- What? - What do you mean what?
我想知道你的想法
I want to know what you think.
我觉得一场重量级比赛
I think I saw a heavyweight fight
马上就要见分晓了
that's gonna come down to the goddamn cards.
你有不同的看法吗
You see it any different?
我的看法是我的命运掌握在了陪审团手里
What I see is my fate in the hands of a jury,
而我不喜欢这样
and I don't like it.
不然你以为我为何
Why the hell do you think
大部分时间都选择和解而不愿上庭
I cut so many deals instead of going to trial?
吉布斯唯一会接受的和解协议
Well, the only deal that Gibbs is going to cut
就是把我们整死
is the one that hangs us out to dry.
我不知道你怎么想
And I don't know about you,
但我可不喜欢就这样坐在一旁
but I don't feel like just sitting by
等着这件事出结果
while this thing goes to verdict.
你以为我喜欢吗
You think I do?
听着  没有其他办...
Look, there's no other w--
等等
Hold on a second.
我们可以把这弄成是无效审判
We could go get us a mistrial.
那样有什么好处
What good would that do?
无效审判不过是缓兵之计
A mistrial's just gonna kick the can down the road
直到迈克再次被审
till Mike gets tried again.
听我说
Listen to me.
在迈克想要代理自己时
when Mike wanted to represent himself,
吉布斯跳起来
Gibbs jumped out of her chair
说我们是在试图把这弄成无效审判
saying that we were trying to get a mistrial.
然后她要求我们放弃申请无效审判的权利
Then she demanded we waive our rights to one completely.
而她之所以这么做
And the only reason she'd do that
是因为她没有权利
is because she doesn't have authorization
再办一次这个案子
to try this case again.
这意味着
Which means,
无效审判不仅仅是缓兵之计
a mistrial isn't just kicking the can down the road.
的确  这可是毁灭性武器
No, it's blowing it to kingdom come.
唯一的问题是
The only problem is,
我们没有理由促成无效审判
we don't have grounds for a mistrial.
那你就最好出去找一些理由
Well, then you better go out and find some.
而且你最好在陪审团回来前就找到
And you better do it before that jury comes back.
我想跟你说的就是这个
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
我的律师不在场
My lawyer's not here.
那可不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
那为什么他告诉我
Then why did he tell me that
假如我和你说他来不了
if I told you he couldn't make it,
你就会让我延期之类的
you'd give me a continuance or something?
我告诉你我会怎么做  迪亚兹先生
I'll tell you what I'll do, Mr. Diaz.
既然珀金斯不在这里
Since Perkins isn't here,
我来帮帮你好了
I'll help you out.
与其上庭  然后
Instead of going to trial and winding up
判一个五年徒刑
with a five year sentence,
我当场就能让你减到三年半
I'll let you cop to three and a half right here.
五年
Five years?
我们只是偷了几台电视
We stole some TVs.
连犯三次  就是五年
For the third time, and that's five years.
我只是给他们开车的
I was only driving the car, man.
那你可以自己开车去监狱了
Then you can drive yourself to prison, man,
但我不会同意延期审理的
but I'm not giving you a continuance.
抱歉打断
Hey, I'm sorry to interrupt,
但延不延期他说了不算  法官说了才算
but he doesn't give you a continuance, the judge does.
而且你可以自动获得延期
And you're entitled to one automatically
如果这是你的律师第一次没有出现
if this is the first time your attorney didn't show.
-你是什么人  -不关你的事
- And who the hell are you? - That's not your concern.
这也不关你的事
And this is not your concern.
我正把它变成我的事
Yeah, well, I'm making it my concern
因为我不愿意看着检察官
since I don't like watching prosecutors
欺骗没有律师的被告人
take advantage of unrepresented defendants.
我不过是向他提出了一个协议
All I'm doing is offering the man a deal.
-没有骗他  -胡说八道
- I'm not taking advantage. - That is bullshit.
你明知他的律师没让他
You know full well his lawyer didn't tell him
向你申请延期
to ask you for a continuance.
而是让他向法官申请
He told him to ask the judge for one.
你却想诓骗他三年半的牢狱之灾
Now you're gonna try and bully him into three and a half years
就为了一起在我听来算是轻微的盗窃罪
for what sounds to me like a simple misdemeanor theft.
你根本不了解这个案子
You don't know shit about this case.
我就要了解了  把相关文件给我
Well, I'm about to. Hand over the case file.
我什么都不会给的
I don't have to give you anything.
你又不是他的律师
You're not his attorney.
迪亚兹先生  我叫迈克·罗斯
Mr. Diaz, my name is Mike Ross.
你是愿意让我为你辩护
Now, do you want me to represent you
还是仍想让那个连你的听证会都不来的混蛋
or do you want to stick with this asshole Perkins
珀金斯继续为你辩护
who didn't even show up to your hearing?
他是我的律师
He's my lawyer.
唐娜  你得马上帮我个忙
Donna, I need your help and I need it right now.
怎么了  陪审团回来了吗
What's going on? Is the jury back?
没  我需要知道斯特芬尼·利斯顿是否还在
No, I need to know if Stephanie Liston still works
-联邦检察官办公室工作  -在  怎么了
- at the U.S. Attorney's office. - She does, why?
我需要陪审团名单
I need the names of the jurors.
哈维  如果你在考虑干扰...
Harvey, if you're even thinking about tampering--
不  我没想干扰陪审团
No, I'm not thinking of tampering with the jury.
我只是得找出申请裁决无效的理由
I just need to find grounds for a mistrial.
裁决无效
A mistrial?
你告诉迈克他成功了是骗他的吗
You told Mike he killed it. Was that a lie?
-不是  -那你为什么
- No, it wasn't. - Then why are you
-突然又犹疑了  -这叫以防万一
- so suddenly having doubts? - It's called hedging.
不  这叫违法行为
No, it is called breaking the law
我不想参与
and I don't want any part of it.
见鬼  唐娜  我是在保护迈克
Goddamn it, Donna. I'm trying to protect Mike.
那你应该合法地申请判决无效
Then maybe you should be getting a mistrial legally
而不是让我去做你要求的事
instead of having me do what you're asking.
-我们没时间了  -我不管
- We don't have time. - I don't care!
你这是怎么了
What the hell's wrong with you?
-我  -对  你
- Me? - Yes, you.
你到底站哪边儿
Whose side are you on?
你居然怀疑我
Oh, don't you dare ask me that.
你明知我会为了你和迈克去犯法
You know damn well that I would break the law for you and Mike,
但你却让我
but you are asking me
去让我的朋友犯法
to have my friend do it,
-我不会这么做的  -唐娜
- and I am not going to. - Donna--
哈维  就算我去找斯特芬尼
Harvey, even if I did ask Stephanie
而且她答应了  但这不可能
and she said yes, which she never would,
你就又把无辜的人
you would have to drag innocent people
牵扯进这个烂摊子了
through the mud to get this done.
我认识的那个哈维
And the Harvey I know
可不是这种人
isn't that kind of person.
唐娜  出什么事了
Donna, what is going on?
-你怎么不高兴  -我没不高兴
- Why are you so upset? - I'm not upset.
你说"我没不高兴"的时候
When you say, "I'm not upset,"
是你演出来的吗  因为烂透了
is that you acting? Because it sucks.
你有事吗  路易
What do you want from me, Louis?
我只想让你少废话  告诉我出了什么事
I want you to cut the bullshit and tell me what's wrong.
我看见你离开哈维的办公室
I just saw you leave Harvey's office
五秒钟以后  他也走了
and five seconds later, I saw him do the same thing.
路易  事情就是哈维希望我
Okay, Louis, what's wrong is Harvey wants me
从我在联邦检察官办公室的朋友那里
to get the names of the jurors from my friend
弄到陪审团名单
in the U.S. Attorney's office.
-他想干扰陪审员吗  -他想争取裁决无效
- He's trying to tamper? - He's trying to get a mistrial.
那你为什么不帮他
Well, then why the hell aren't you helping him do it?
-什么  -你没听错
- What? - You heard me.
你为什么不竭尽所能帮他
Why aren't you doing whatever you can do help him?
难以置信你居然对我说这种话
I can't believe you just said that to me.
唐娜  听我说  如果哈维这么做
Donna, listen to me, if Harvey's doing this,
说明他觉得自己要输了
it means he thinks he's going to lose.
如果他觉得自己要输
And if he thinks he's gonna lose,
就说明他一定会输
it means he is gonna lose.
如果迈克被定罪
And if Mike goes down,
所有人都得给他陪葬
everybody goes down with him.
你就一点都不在乎吗
Don't you care about that at all?
我真有点受够了被人问
I'm getting a little tired of people asking me
我在不在乎  因为我在乎
whether I care or not. Because I do,
但还没在乎到为了保自己
But not enough to push women and children aside
就拉无辜的人下水
to get on a lifeboat.
如果你找我就是为了这个
So, if that's all you came in here to ask me,
别费口舌赶紧走吧
why don't you be on your way?
我买了些面包
Okay, I got us some bread,
奶酪  一点红酒和一张野餐垫
cheese, a little bit of wine, and a picnic blanket.
我们可以去外面...
So, I feel like we should just go outside--
-我去不了  -什么叫去不了
- I can't. - What do you mean you can't?
陪审团回来了吗
Did the jury come back?
没有  我遇见一个被告
No, I, uh, I met a defendant.
因为小偷小摸被抓了
He got caught in the act of some petty larceny,
他们想逼他认罪  所以我...
and, uh, they're trying to railroad him, so I--
所以你就接了这个案子
So, you're taking a case?
瑞秋  他只是想偷偷地
Rachel, he tried to sell a couple of TVs
卖几台电视  现在却面临五年的徒刑
out of the back of a truck. Now he's facing five years.
这栋楼里某个地方  正有12个人
And somewhere in this building there are 12 people
决定着你是不是个骗子
deciding whether or not you're a fraud
而你却坐在这里做着
and you're sitting here doing the exact thing
他们指控你的事
that they're accusing you of.
他们就在我眼前
They were right in front of me.
他的律师没来
His lawyer didn't show up--
-你是怎么了  -瑞秋
- What is wrong with you? - Whoa, Rachel, hey--
你不知道我害怕吗
Don't you understand that I am scared,
我还努力支持你
and that I am trying to be supportive
强装着勇敢
and to keep a brave face,
尽管我可能会失去你  迈克
but that I could lose you, Mike?
我理解你想待在这里
So, I understand you wanting to be here,
但我无法理解你不想陪着我
but I don't understand you not wanting to be with me.
过来
Come here.
我也害怕
Look, I'm scared too.
所以我才不能回家
That's why I can't go home.
我不知道我是如何卷进这场纷争  但是
And I don't know how I got into this, but...
我知道我必须这样做  瑞秋
I know that I need to do this, Rachel.
你对陪审团说的那些话都是认真的  对吗
You really meant what you said to the jury, didn't you?
没错
Yeah.
而且你说过你爱上我
And you said that you fell in love with me
是因为我想帮助别人
because of me wanting to help other people.
那这个人需要我的帮助
Well, this guy needs my help.
而且这或许是我最后一次可以这样做了
And it may be the last time I can do something like this.
那么  我们一起想办法帮助他
Well, then let's figure out a way to help him together.
午饭吃的什么  大卫
What's for lunch, David?
藜麦沙拉
Quinoa salad.
那好  慢慢享用
Well, enjoy it,
因为这将是你担任纽约市检察官的最后一顿饭
because it's gonna be your last meal as a U.S. Attorney.
迈克·罗斯答应过我
Mike Ross promised me
如果我给他那些通话记录
that if I gave him those phone records,
他不会对任何人讲
he wouldn't say anything to anyone.
我可不是迈克·罗斯
I'm not Mike Ross,
在我看来
and the way I see it,
我没有理由不把你肮脏的过去告诉给吉布斯
there's no reason for me not to tell Gibbs about your shady past
除非你给我一个理由
unless you give me a reason.
那我应该怎么办
And how am I supposed to do that?
打包起你的午饭
You pack up your lunch,
把它带到街边的那个法院咖啡馆
you take it down the street to the courthouse cafe,
当他们在两个小时后出来在那儿喝咖啡时
and you share a table with whatever juror shows up
你就和随便哪个陪审员坐在一起
when they break for coffee in about two hours.
这是干什么
What's this for?
拿去给随便哪个陪审员买一杯咖啡
For when you buy juror number whatever a cup of coffee.
老天啊  你想让我制造一场无效判决
Jesus christ, you want me to give you a mistrial?
这样做我可能会失去工作
I do that, I could lose my job.
但你不那样做  两小时后你会失去自由
You're gonna lose your freedom in two hours if you don't.
这是敲诈勒索
This is blackmail.
我说这叫赎罪
I call it atonement,
你将在今天接受应得的惩罚
and today's the day you face the music.
-你说得对  -关于什么
- You were right. - About what?
我真不应该为了达到目的
I shouldn't have been willing to hurt innocent people
而伤害一些无辜之人
to get done what I needed to get done.
好吧  但听上去你还是做了
Well, it sounds like you got it done anyway.
没错  只要凡妮莎拿到我需要的照片
I did, and you're gonna get a call from Vanessa
你就会接到她的电话
as soon as she gets me some pictures I need.
哈维  你刚才还在说你不应该
Harvey, you just said that you shouldn't have been willing
伤害无辜之人
to hurt innocent people, and--
我没有伤害任何无辜之人  唐娜
I didn't hurt any innocent people, Donna.
我找了一个有罪之人
I found a guilty one.
那好  那我会告诉杰西卡
Well, then I will go tell Jessica
凡妮莎一打电话来我就告诉你
and I will let you know the second Vanessa calls.
唐娜
Donna.
什么  哈维
What, Harvey?
谢谢
Thanks.
真不敢相信我们找到了
I can't believe we found that.
真不敢相信你做到了
I can't believe you did.
瑞秋  我们可能可以用这个优势
Rachel, this might give us the leverage
确保迪亚兹根本不用坐牢
to make sure Diaz doesn't do any jail time at all.
-你真这样想吗  -没错
- Do you really think so? - Yeah, I do.
而且我一点不感到意外
And it doesn't surprise me
因为我同样觉得你会成为一名出色的律师
'cause I also think that you're gonna make a great lawyer.
那么  我们把时间花在这上面
Well, then spending our time doing this
也许并不是一个坏主意
wasn't such a bad idea after all.
迪亚兹先生  你准备好进行辩护了
Mr. Diaz, are you ready to enter a plea?
在辩护之前  法官大人  我想提交一份申请
Before we do, Your Honor, I'd like to enter a motion
撤销对迪亚兹先生的汽车的搜查
to invalidate the search of Mr. Diaz's vehicle.
-什么  -搜查令的取得
- What? - The warrant was obtained
全是因为我当事人和他表兄之间的一通电话
because of a phone call between my client and his cousin,
而且没有任何证据表明亚历山大先生
and there's no evidence that Mr. Alexander
有权窃听那通电话
had authorization to tap that call.
法官大人  我们有其他证据支撑搜查令
Your Honor, we had other sources for our search warrant.
-那到底是什么  -亚历山大先生
- And what exactly were they? - Mr. Alexander?
反对  法官大人
Objection, Your Honor.
吉布斯女士  这个案子
Ms. Gibbs, this case isn't
并不在司法部的管辖内
under the Justice Department's jurisdiction,
那么  你到底在反对什么呢
so, what exactly are you objecting to?
我反对的是这个人根本不是律师
I'm objecting to the fact that this man is not a lawyer.
法官大人  那是谎言
Your Honor, that is a lie.
现在  陪审团正在对他进行定罪
And as we speak, a jury is finding him guilty.
在他们定罪之前  我的律师证编号有效
And until they do, my bar number is active.
这太荒唐了  法官大人
This is ridiculous, Your Honor.
他这是在愚弄整个法庭
He is making a mockery of this entire courtroom,
奈特法官
我强烈要求在对他的审讯结果出来以前
and I urge you to at least delay this case
你至少应该延迟审理本案
until his jury comes back.
法官大人  我之所以要为迪亚兹先生辩护
Your Honor, the only reason I'm representing Mr. Diaz,
是因为法院指派的律师没有出现
is because his court-appointed lawyer didn't show up,
然后那个人企图迫使他仓促地
and then that man attempted to railroad him
签订一份离谱的认罪协议
into an outrageous plea deal.
吉布斯女士  他在你的审理中可能是名骗子
Ms. Gibbs, he may be a fraud in your court,
但是既然他还没有被认定任何罪名
but since he hasn't been convicted of anything,
他在我的法庭内就是一名律师
he isn't one in mine.
除非亚历山大在此能够出示证据
And unless Mr. Alexander here magically finds his voice,
批准通过罗斯先生
Mr. Ross's motion
申请排除对他当事人的汽车搜查证据的动议
to exclude the search of his clients vehicle passes.
那个女人说的是真话吗
Is it true what that woman was saying?
没错  他们正在审查要不要毁掉他的人生
Yes, they're deliberating on his fate right now.
我才不关心他们在审查什么
I don't give a shit if they're deliberating.
他到底是不是假冒的
Is he a fake or not?
你亲眼看到了  他正要为你达成协议
You saw what he just did, and he's about to cut you a deal
或许让你的牢狱之灾从四年变成几个月
from four years behind bars to maybe a few months.
那么你认为呢
So what do you think?
他说什么了
What'd he say?
他现在太生气没办法达成协议
He's too pissed off to make a deal right now,
但相信我  他会冷静下来  然后达成协议
but trust me, he'll calm down, and then he will.
迈克  你要去哪儿
Mike, where are you going?
我要试着为我自己达成协议
I'm gonna go try and make a deal of my own.
你走得太快
You ran out of there so fast
我都没机会和你说话
I didn't get a chance to talk to you.
你到底想干吗  罗斯先生
What exactly do you want, Mr. Ross?
我想跟你签个协议
I want to make a deal.
你终于准备好出卖斯佩克特先生了
You finally ready to turn on Mr. Specter?
不  但我愿意承认有罪
Nope, but I am ready to plead guilty
而且永不做律师
and never practice law again
只要你答应
if you agree
不再对付任何皮尔森-斯佩克特的合伙人
to not go after any of the partners at Person Specter.
在我第一次遇见他的时候
That's the same bullshit your boss said to me
你老板也说过这句废话
when I first met him.
你不做律师了
You're done practicing,
我就应该让你全身而退吗
so I should just let you get away with it?
既然我那时没有听他的话
Why would I listen to you now
为何现在要听你的呢
if I didn't listen to him then?
因为你都写在了脸上
Because you've got it written all over your face.
看见我做律师让你恶心
Seeing me be a lawyer makes you sick.
对吗  如果我赢了
Right? And if I win,
我会继续当律师
I'm gonna keep being a lawyer,
那样会让你一辈子都恶心
and it's gonna make you sick for the rest of your life.
不行  理由不够充分
No deal. It's not a good enough reason.
行  那试试这个
Okay, then let's try this one.
你在联邦检察官办公室很长时间
You've been at the same level at the U.S. Attorney's office
没升职了
for a long time.
起诉一个公认的骗子
Now, a person who can't get a conviction
还没法给他定罪的检察官
against a man that everyone thinks is a fraud,
就走投无路了
well, that's a person who's going nowhere.
这是你挽回颜面的机会
This is a chance for you to save face.
我不需要挽回颜面
I don't need to save face
因为他们会判你有罪
because they're gonna find you guilty.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
你连说服一个法官让我离席都做不到
'cause you couldn't convince one judge to make me stand down,
凭什么觉得自己能说服十二个陪审员呢
so what makes you think you're gonna convince 12 jurors?
你要知道  迈克
You know what, Mike?
事实是
The truth is,
你本可以成为好律师的
you would have made a good lawyer,
但你并不是
but you're not one,
我会把你送进监狱
and I'm gonna put you away.
有什么事  唐娜
What can I do for you, Donna?
哈维让我告诉你
Harvey wanted me to let you know that
只要接下来几个小时没有判决
as long as they don't reach a verdict in the next few hours,
-你这个案子就会成为无效判决  -无效判决
- you'll have a mistrial. - I'll have a mistrial?
-你在想什么  唐娜  -没什么
- What's on your mind, Donna? - Nothing.
大概就是我从没想到会看到有一天
I guess I just never thought I'd see the day
你认为哈维会输
when you thought Harvey was gonna lose.
谁说我觉得哈维会输
And who says I think Harvey's going to lose?
-无效判决啊  -不
- A mistrial says it. - No,
这只说明我不想在十二个陌生人身上冒险
it says I'm not willing to take a chance on 12 complete strangers.
这说明你对他没信心
It says you don't have faith in him.
唐娜  这话说得有点离谱
Donna, you don't know what you're saying.
是吗  我知道我不是名律师
Don't I? I know I'm not a lawyer,
但如果迈克无罪  当然不会对他
but isn't it true that if Mike gets found innocent,
进行再次审理吗  但如果判决无效
there's no double jeopardy, but if a mistrial happens,
他们未来可能还会查他
they might come after him again one day?
没错  唐娜
Yes, Donna, that is true,
但我和哈维都坚信那不会发生
but Harvey and I are banking that never happens.
-那如果发生了呢  -那我很遗憾
- And what if it does? - Then I'm sorry,
但事实是  是迈克·罗斯
but the truth is, Mike Ross is the reason
当初让我们陷入困境
why we're in this mess in the first place,
如果现在要在
and if it's a choice
我和他之间选一个以后能高枕无忧的人
between his peace of mind down the road and mine today,
我会选自己
I'm choosing mine.
还有事吗
Now, is that all?
路易·利特  真巧
Louis Litt, what a coincidence,
我刚准备给你办公室打电话  假装是你表亲
I was just about to call your office, say I was your cousin,
问你决定要不要接受我的提议
and ask if you'd decided to take me up on my offer.
我回答你之前  我想知道
Before I give you an answer, I want to know,
如果我能向你证实哈维清楚迈克的身份
if I give you proof that Harvey knew about Mike,
-你会给我豁免权吗  -要看情况
- will you give me immunity? - Well, that depends.
你有什么证据
What do you have?
什么叫我有什么证据
What do you mean, what do I have?
我就足够了
I have me.
这还不够充分
Well, that's not good enough.
那你到底找我干什么
Well, then what the hell did you come to me for?
因为我期待的不只是
Because I was expecting something more
想要自救之人的证词
than the testimony of a man who's saving his own ass,
那对我毫无用处
which gets me nothing.
毫无用处  我会给你证词
Nothing? I'd be giving you my word.
我不需要你的证词  我需要证据
And I don't need your word. I need proof.
该死  我没有证据
Well, goddamn it, I don't have any proof.
那你对我没有用处
Well, then you're no good to me.
我现在为了搞垮你和你合伙人
And now I'm in the position of having to work that much harder
我不得不更加努力工作
to get both you and your partners,
请见谅  我得继续工作了  路易
so, if you'll excuse me, I need to get back to it, Louis.
唐娜  你马上开始准备
Donna, I need you to start prepping a motion
迈克申请裁判无效的动议
for Mike to ask for a mistrial,
这是我们明早要做的第一件事
And we're gonna need to do it first thing in the morning.
哈维  我觉得裁判不会无效
Harvey, I don't think there's gonna be a mistrial.
这话是什么意思
What the hell are you talking about?
我刚和凡妮莎通完电话
I just got off the phone with Vanessa.
大卫·格林没现身
David Green never showed.
不管什么事  路易
Whatever it is, Louis,
我都没空
I don't have the time.
你最好抽空
Well, you better find the time
因为安妮塔·吉布斯要跟我做交易
because Anita Gibbs just offered me a deal.
我觉得你会狠狠拒绝她
And I assume you told her to shove it up her ass.
没错  但我其实想问
I did, but what I really wanted to say was,
"在哪里签字"
"Where do I sign?"
你刚跟我说了什么
What the hell did you just say to me?
你有没有考虑过
Did you ever think for one second,
如果迈克被定罪会怎样
what's gonna happen if Mike gets convicted?
迈克不会被定罪
Mike is not gonna get convicted.
-你怎么这么确定  -因为我要申请
- How could you be so sure? - Because I'm gonna go get us
-该死的裁判无效  -那还不够
- a goddamn mistrial. - That's not good enough.
我想知道你打算怎么做
I want to know how you're gonna do that.
-与你无关  -与我有关
- None of your business. - It is my business.
如果你要违反更多法律
If you're gonna go and break some more laws
就像你当初雇那个骗子一样
like you did when you hired the fraud in the first place.
你到底想干什么  路易
What the hell do you want, Louis?
你想让我同意你去做交易码
You want me to give you permission to cut a deal?
我希望你去自首
I want you to give yourself up.
-你疯了吗  -我很清醒
- Are you out of your mind? - No, I am in my mind.
如果你申请不到无效裁判  判决反咬一口
You can't get a mistrial, that verdict comes back the wrong way,
整个律所的人都会因为你的所作所为
everyone in this entire firm goes to jail
进监狱
because of what you did.
-回家吧  路易  -不  不行
- Go home, Louis. - No, no, no,
我要你亲口说出来
I want you to say it.
你私自雇了一个骗子
You went out on your own, you hired a fraud,
整个律所为此付出代价
and this whole firm's paying for it.
-闭嘴吧  -只有你
- Shut the hell up. - You and you alone
要为接下来的灾难负责
are responsible for the carnage of what's to come.
-路易  -你说啊
- Louis-- - Just say it!
你听着  我或许雇了个骗子
You listen to me. I may have hired a fraud,
但你才是那个本有可能告发他
but you're the one who had the chance to turn him in
却利用他的秘密实现你一直以来的目的人
and you used his secret to get what you always wanted.
所以  别半夜十一点跑来这里
So, don't come here at the 11th hour
把账赖到我头上  这是你自作自受
trying to blame me for having to sleep in the bed that you made.
我不想进监狱  哈维
I don't want to go to prison, harvey.
那就别挡路  让我想办法
Then get out of my way, and let me do what I do.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
跟你谈谈
I came to talk.
我不得不说
I gotta hand it to you,
你本可以做个好律师
you would have made a good lawyer,
但你比我认为的更出色
but you're even better than I gave you credit for.
我考虑了你说的
You got in my head.
你要接受我的提议吗
You came here to take my offer?
我是来给你我自己的提议
I came to make an offer of my own.
你说你想要给我机会挽回颜面
You said you were giving me a chance to save face,
但如果我让你免受惩罚
but I let you get off with no punishment.
就我的职业生涯来看
As far as my career goes,
那和你被判无罪也没什么区别
I might as well have let them find you innocent.
你想怎样
What do you want?
你认罪  坐两年牢
You plead guilty, do two years in prison,
我就放过你的朋友们
and I won't go after any of your friends.
我是不会因为我没犯过的罪
There's no way I agree to prison time
而去监狱坐牢的
for a crime I didn't commit.
我们现在不是在庭上  迈克
We're not in the courtroom right now, Mike,
所以废话少说
so let's cut the bullshit.
你我心知肚明你是犯了事的
We both know you did this.
如果你不想付出相应的代价
So if you don't want to pay,
那就接受我一开始的提议
then you take me up on my original offer.
根本不用坐牢
You do no time,
我要的回报也只是一个你们律所的命名合伙人
and all I need in return is one name partner at your firm.
但我也告诉你了那是不可能的
And I told you that's never gonna happen.
那你可能想跟你的未婚妻谈谈
Well, maybe you want to talk to your fiancé
因为她的表情表明
because the look on her face says
她情愿把他们扔给狼群
she'd rather throw one of them to the wolves
也不愿看你坐牢
then see you in prison.
所以决定权在你
So it's up to you.
你可以接受我两个提议中的任何一个
You take either one of my deals,
也可以去陪审团那里碰碰运气
or you take your chances with the jury.
但记住
Just remember,
时间不等人
tick tock.
哪里来"两个提议"
What did she mean, "Either deal"?
她针对我的提议又提了一个
She countered my offer.
-多久  -瑞秋
- How long? - Rachel--
你要走多久
How long would you have to be away for?
-两年  -不  迈克
- Two years. - No, Mike.
-不  不行  -你知道
- No, you can't. - Do you know
如果我被判有罪  要蹲多少年吗
how much time I'm facing if I'm found guilty?
你不会被判有罪的
You're not gonna be found guilty.
七年
Seven years.
你不会被判有罪的
You're not gonna be found guilty.
我看到你上庭的样子了  你很棒的
I saw you up there. You were amazing.
你还是当初我爱上的那个
You were that same empathetic, brilliant man
那个善解人意  才华横溢的男人
that I fell in love with.
没道理陪审团的人看不出来
There's no way the jury didn't see that.
瑞秋  陪审团又没爱上我
Rachel, the jury is not in love with me.
万一他们看着我时看到的是
What if all they saw when they looked at me
那个自第一天接下这工作
was the same fraud that I've been
就一直在欺骗众人的我呢
since the first day I took that job?
这就是你为什么在考虑去坐牢吗
Is that why you're thinking about going to prison?
因为什么  因为你想惩罚自己
Because what? You want to punish yourself
而坐牢是唯一能让你不再愧疚的办法吗
and that's your only way to stop feeling guilty?
是的  可能有部分这个原因吧
Yes, maybe that's a part of it.
是吗  但听着好像就是这个原因啊
Okay, well it sounds like it's all of it.
我只知道  这是唯一有把握的方法
All I know, is it's the only sure way
让事情归于平息  并且能保证
to put this to bed and make sure that
受损失的只有我一人
the only person who is hurt by it is me.
那我呢
What about me?
我也只是爱你啊
Because all I did was love you!
如果你答应了什么送你去坐牢的协议
And if you take some deal that sends you to prison--
瑞秋  我们能撑过去的
Rachel, we can survive this--
该死的  迈克  这事儿他们也有一份啊
Goddamn it, Mike, they were in on it too!
我不会出卖他们的
I'm not gonna rat them out.
我不是劝你出卖他们
And I'm not asking you to.
我只是希望你能对自己多点信心
I'm just asking you to have faith in yourself.
好  我会的
Okay, I will.
你去哪儿了
Where the hell were you?
你是说我没在那家咖啡馆吗
You mean why I wasn't at the cafe?
我只是得出结论
I was just coming to the conclusion
你还是收回你的威胁  拿回家擦屁股去吧
that you could take that threat and shove it up your ass.
你以为我是在唬你吗
You think I'm bluffing you?
我管你是不是在唬我
I don't give a shit whether you're bluffing or not.
想到让迈克·罗斯上庭我就恶心
It made me sick to let Mike Ross back into a court.
我不会再让这种事发生了
I'm not letting that happen again.
我觉得你好像没有理解我明早打给
I don't think you understand what's gonna happen to you
安妮塔·吉布斯后你的下场
when I call Anita Gibbs tomorrow morning.
你没犯过错吗
You never made a mistake?
你没做过让自己后悔的事吗
You never did something you regret?
不然你以为我现在费心补救什么
What do you think I'm trying to fix right now?
听着  如果你不帮我的话
Look, if you don't help me,
那么我可是一点都不会后悔
making sure you never practice law again
确保你以后都干不成律师
isn't gonna be on my list of regrets.
我听过好多人说
You know, I've heard a lot of people talk
哈维·斯佩克特的厉害  说他战无不胜
about the great Harvey Specter, completely unbeatable.
但就我看来
From what I'm seeing,
他不过是一个恶霸  利用他人弱点
you're just a bully who uses other people's fears
来得到自己想要的东西
to get what he wants.
只可惜  今晚你不会得逞了
Well, it's not gonna happen tonight,
因为迈克·罗斯就要进监狱了
because Mike Ross is about to go to prison
而我也不会阻止此事
and I'm not going to stop him.
哈维  这大半夜的
Harvey, it's the middle of the night.
-你来这儿干吗  -我得见你
- What are you doing here? - I had to see you.
我知道你说过我不能再这么做了
I know you said I couldn't do this anymore,
但我得跟你谈谈
but I need to talk to you.
-谈什么  -谈我要怎么做
- Talk about what? - About what I have to do.
你准备自首了  是不是
You're gonna turn yourself in, aren't you?
路易  陪审团没有回来
Louis, the jury didn't come back,
既然他们已经回家了
and since they went home,
我现在也要回家
I'm going home.
不管什么事  明天早上再说
So, whatever it is, it's gonna have to wait until tomorrow.
明天就太迟了
Tomorrow could be too late.
什么太迟了
Too late for what?
这都是他的错
This is all his fault.
不是你起的头
You didn't start it.
也不是我起的头
I didn't start it.
是他起的头
He started it.
我不会背着哈维
I'm not having this conversation
-跟你谈这件事的  -没关系
- behind Harvey's back. - That's okay.
我已经跟他说过了
I already had it to his face.
希望能让他做出正确的选择
Tried to get him to do the right thing
然后自首  但他不愿意
and turn himself in, but he wouldn't.
我不会劝他去自首的
I'm not going to convince him to do that.
我知道  因为他从来都不听劝
I know, because he'll never be convinced.
所以我们才要一起去找吉布斯
Which is why we need to go to Gibbs together--
-路易  -该死的  杰西卡
- Louis-- - Goddamn it, Jessica,
我们没时间了
we don't have any time!
你有没有想到过
Did it ever occur to you
如果迈克被判有罪
that if Mike gets found guilty,
哈维会做的第一件事
the first thing Harvey is going to do
就是走进那里  为我和你挡下这一切
is walk in there and take the bullet for me and you?
-我没想到过  -可我想到了
- No, it didn't. - Well, it occurred to me.
如果我们现在背叛他
We turn on him now,
那我们也没有比丹尼尔·哈德曼
we're not better than Daniel Hardman
或者查尔斯·傅滋曼
or Charles Forstman
或任何一个你鄙视的人好到哪里去
or any of those other people you despise.
你还没看出来吗
Don't you see?
我们是可以互相保护的
We could protect each other.
你不是希望我们互相保护  路易
You don't want us to protect each other, Louis.
你是希望有人告诉你
You want someone to tell you
你的想法没有问题
that what you're thinking is okay,
但我不会那么说的
and I'm not going to do that.
杰西卡  拜托了
Jessica, please.
晚安  路易
Good night, Louis.
你因为某个作弊者说你
So you want to turn yourself in
是个恶棍就想去自首吗
because some cheater called you a bully?
不  唐娜  我自首是因为
No, Donna, I want to turn myself in
他说的没错  我不是不可战胜的
because he was right. I'm not unbeatable.
不  哈维  我觉得是他让你觉得愧疚
No, Harvey, I think he made you feel guilty,
而你没法看清情况了
and now you're not seeing clearly.
-唐娜  -哈维  如果不是迈克而是别人受审
- Donna-- - Harvey, if it were anybody other than Mike on trial
而你看了他的结案陈词
and you saw his closing,
你觉得陪审团会给他定罪吗
do you think that the jury would convict him?
我不知道  唐娜  但我不能
I don't know, Donna, but I can't afford
承受出错的后果
to be wrong about this.
那我问你一句
Then let me as you a question:
你为什么不跟阿加德医生聊这事
why aren't you talking to dr. Agard about this?
-你怎么知道她的  -我就是知道
- How do you know about her? - Because I do.
我还知道你上次做重大决定时
And I also know that the last time you had
是去找了她  而不是我
a huge decision to make, you went to her and not me.
因为上次是公事
Because that was about business
-这次是私事  -不 哈维
- and this is personal. - No, Harvey,
你没去找她是因为你知道
you didn't go to her because you know she won't try
她不会试图劝阻你  但我会
to talk you out of this, but I will.
-唐娜  -别那么做
- Donna-- - Don't do it.
别再自愿承担后果了
Don't fall on your sword again.
-我必须...  -你不必
- I have to-- - No, you don't.
我们可能赢不了
We might not win.
你不需要永远都做英雄
You don't always have to be the hero.
我那么做不是为了当英雄
I'm not doing it to be the hero.
那你为了什么
Then why the hell are you doing it?
因为是我自己犯的错
Because it's my goddamn fault.
不  哈维  不是你的错
No, Harvey, it's not.
那是你和迈克两人的错
It's Mike's fault just as much as it is yours.
那为什么要我来将他推进火坑
Then why should I be the one to throw him under the bus?
你不明白吗  我不是要你
Don't you get it? I am not asking you
将他推进火坑
to throw him under the bus.
我是请求你
I am asking you
相信你们两人
to believe that the two of you
值得被判无罪
are worthy of being found innocent.
如果我做不到呢
And what if I can't do that?
那你可以等早上再去吉布斯办公室
Then you can march yourself down to Gibbs's office
把自己交出去
in the morning and turn yourself in.
但我不希望你那么做
But I don't want you to do that.
为什么
Why not?
因为我觉得你应该被判无罪
Because I think you're worthy.
我也不希望失去你
And I don't want to lose you.
哈维
Harvey,
明早去法院
go to the courthouse in the morning,
跟迈克一起坐下来  等判决出来
sit with Mike until that verdict comes in,
让他看到你对他有信心
and show him that you have faith in him.
就像我对你有信心一样
Like I have faith in you.
你好
Hello?
对  我是
Yeah, this is him.
好  我马上到
Yeah, yeah, I'll be right there.
陪审团怎么这么快就出来了
How's the jury back so early?
不是陪审团
Oh, it's not the jury.
是迪亚兹案的检察官
It's the prosecutor from the Diaz case.
他想跟我聊聊
He wants to talk.
我或许雇了个骗子
I may have hired a fraud,
但你才是那个有机会告发他
but you're the one who had the chance to turn him in,
却你利用他的秘密实现你一直以来的目的人
and you used his secret to get what you always wanted...
-利特先生  -别半夜十一点来这里
- Mr. Litt... - so don't come in here--
很抱歉打扰你
I'm sorry to interrupt,
但你表妹格特鲁德打来电话了
but your cousin Gertrude's on the phone.
她说她需要确定
She said she needs to know
你找到她那盘旧混音带没
whether you found that old mixed tape of hers.
告诉她没找到
Tell her I didn't.
告诉她肯定是被扔掉了
Tell her it must have gotten thrown out,
让她别再问我了
and to never ask me about it again.
-好的  -什么好
- Good. - What do you mean "Good"?
从这事一开始  我就想告诉安妮塔·吉布斯
I been wanting to tell Anita Gibbs to go to hell
让她下地狱去
since this whole thing started.
罗斯先生
Mr. Ross,
我想给你当事人一个协议
I'd like to make your client an offer.
我们在听
We're listening.
我们不想抓你  迪亚兹先生
We don't want you, Mr. Diaz.
你说你只是在开车  我们相信你
You said you were just driving the truck and I believe you,
我们已经抓到了
and we already have the two gentleman
两位犯下重罪的男士
who committed the actual felony.
所以你要做的  就是指证他们
So, all you have to do is testify against them,
-然后就可以走了  -什么
- and you walk. - What?
老天  不用坐牢吗
Holy shit. No jail time?
-不用  -好  那就够了
- No jail time. - Okay that's enough.
-我需要跟我当事人谈谈  -不  我不用谈
- I need a moment with my client. - No, I don't need a moment.
-我接受  -迪亚兹先生  听我说
- I'll take it. - Mr. Diaz, listen to me.
指证你的朋友在目前看来可能不是大事
Testifying against your friends may not seem like a big deal
但你今后一生都要背负
right now, but it's something you are gonna have to live with
-这个罪孽  -我什么都不欠他们
- for the rest of your life. - I don't owe them anything,
如果我能自己脱罪  我就做
and if I can get myself off, that's what I'm gonna do.
他给你这个协议
He's only offering you this
只是因为他没有起诉你们的证据
because he doesn't have a case against you.
他已经输掉两个案子  我会让他再输一次
He's a two-time loser. I'll make a case against him.
迪亚兹先生
Mr. Diaz...
把笔给我
Give me the pen.
你在犯大错
You are making a huge mistake.
我不这么想
Yeah, well, I don't think so,
如果你在我的立场  你也会做一样的事
and if you were in my shoes, you'd do the exact same thing.
我绝不会把朋友送进监狱的
I would never send my friends to prison.
如果他们给我定罪
Yeah, well, they find me guilty,
也一样会送我朋友进监狱
they're gonna send my friends to prison anyways.
哈维  谢天谢地
Harvey, thank God.
陪审团出来了  我们有一小时时间
The jury came back. We have an hour.
-迈克呢  -我不知道
- Where's Mike? - I don't know.
出什么事了
What's the matter?
哈维
Harvey?
我得走了
I have to go.
又回来了  不是吗
Another back, right?
我不在乎
I don't care.
我准备好接受协议了
I'm ready to take your deal.
哪个协议
Which one?